Lowell Nesbitt
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Lowell Nesbitt papers
circa 1903-1993 (bulk 1950-1993)
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Nesbitt, Lowell
48.3 linear feet
The papers of painter, photographer and sculptor Lowell Nesbitt measure 48.3 linear feet and date from circa 1903-1993 (bulk 1950-1993). The collection documents Nesbitt's career through biographical material, correspondence, subject files, business and financial records, source material, artwork, photographs and audiovisual records, printed material and scrapbooks.
Provenance
A portion of the papers were donated by Lowell Nesbitt in 1984 and the bulk of the papers were a bequest from Nesbitt's estate in 1994.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Painter, photographer, and sculptor Lowell Nesbitt worked primarily in New York City.
Lowell Nesbitt was born in Baltimore, Maryland, in 1933. In college he studied stained glass and printmaking, graduating from the Tyler School of Art at Temple University in Philadelphia in 1955 and attending the Royal College of Art in London from 1955 to 1956.
After serving for several years in the United States Army in the mid 1950s, Nesbitt received his first exhibition at the Baltimore Museum of Art in 1958. By 1963 he had moved to New York City and by the 1970s had emerged as one of the most well known artists in the United States. Nesbitt was frequently grouped with the photo realists and was best known for more than four hundred works he created with the flower as his central theme. In addition to flowers, Nesbitt's subjects included studio interiors, dogs, fruits and vegetables, bridges and buildings in New York, and male nudes. He began experimenting with printmaking in the 1960s and produced more than a hundred original prints in the course of his lifetime, primarily in the medium of dry point engraving. In 1963 he began a series of x-ray inspired paintings and was credited with being the first artist to produce a body of work of this kind. During the same period he began a long-standing relationship with the Howard Wise Gallery in New York, a space known for it's devotion to art and new technology.
In 1969 and 1970 the National Aeronautics and Space Administration named Nesbitt the official artist of the Apollo 9 and Apollo 13 missions. In 1980 the United States Postal Service released a series of four postage stamps based on his floral paintings.
Following a major one-man show at the Corcoran Gallery in Washington, DC in 1964, Nesbitt's work was exhibitied widely in Europe and the United States. In New York City he was represented by the Stable Gallery, the Robert Stefanotti Gallery and the Andrew Crispo Gallery. In the late 1960s and early 1970s Nesbitt taught at Towson State and Morgan State Colleges in Maryland, and the School of Visual Arts in New York.
Nesbitt was active in the National Multiple Sclerosis Society from the early 1980s until his death, serving as co-chairman on the Society's annual juried Project Rembrandt exhibition for artists with multiple sclerosis. He was also actively involved in fundraising for artists with HIV/AIDS.
Nesbitt's work is represented in many major museum collections including the Art Institute of Chicago, Baltimore Museum of Art, Bibliotheque Nationale (Paris), Corcoran Gallery, Detroit Institute of Art, Hirshhorn Museum, Museum of Modern Art, and the National Gallery.
Lowell Nesbitt died in 1993 at the age of 59.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of painter, photographer and sculptor Lowell Nesbitt measure 48.3 linear feet and date from circa 1903-1993 (bulk 1950-1993). The collection documents Nesbitt's career through biographical material, correspondence, subject files, business and financial records, source material, artwork, printed matter, photographs and audiovisual records and scrapbooks.
Biographical Material includes documentation of Nesbitt's education and other personal documents. Plans and designs for Nesbitt's properties on West Twelfth Street, New York City and Kent, New York are arranged in the series for architectural records for homes and studios
Correspondence and Subject Files are voluminous and record Nesbitt's interaction with individuals, businesses and organizations and includes personal and family correspondence in addition to correspondence relating to galleries, exhibitions, commissions he undertook and committees on which he served.
Artwork by Nesbitt includes a small collection of collages, drawings, paintings, prints and sketchbooks. Source material comprises approximately 11 linear feet of material, primarily newspaper and magazine clippings and photographs, relating to a large variety of subjects that inspired Nesbitt, such as flowers, fruits and vegetables, dogs and other animals and the studios of other artists including Robert Indiana, Jasper Johns and Andy Warhol.
Photographs are of Nesbitt, his friends, family, colleagues and his pets, as well as subjects of interest to him in his work. Also of note are twenty-seven folders of photographs taken by photographer Jack Mitchell of Nesbitt and others.
Printed Material contains publicity material and documents exhibitions of Nesbitt's work. Additional photographs and printed material are found in the Scrapbooks.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following index terms.
Subjects:
Indiana, Robert, 1928-; Johns, Jasper, 1930-; Warhol, Andy, 1928--Photographs
Subjects-Topical:
Artists' studios--Photographs; Painters--New York (State)--New York; Photographers--New York (State)--New York; Sculptors--New York (State)--New York--Interviews
Types of Materials:
Collages; Designs; Drawings; Paintings; Photographs; Prints; Scrapbooks; Sketchbooks; Sound recordings; Video recordings
Names:
Mitchell, Jack, 1925-
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 11 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1932-1988 (Boxes 1, 40, OV 58; 1.0 linear ft.)
Series 2: Architectural Records for Homes and Studios, 1977-1992 (Boxes 1-2, 40; 1.0 linear ft.)
Series 3: Notes and Writings, 1981-1990 (Boxes 2-3; 1.0 linear ft.)
Series 4: Calendars and Addressess, 1973-1993 (Boxes 3-5; 1.25 linear ft.)
Series 5: Correspondence and Subject Files, 1940-circa 1990s (Boxes 5-12, 40, OV 51; 8.0 linear feet)
Series 6: Business and Financial Records, circa 1910-1993 (Boxes 12-14; 2.0 linear ft.)
Series 7: Artwork, circa 1948-1989 (Boxes 15-16, 41-42, OVs 52, 55; 2.0 linear ft.)
Series 8: Source Material, 1965-circa 1990s (Boxes 16-26, 43-45, OV 53; 12.0 linear ft.)
Series 9: Photographs and Audiovisual Records, 1965-circa 1990s (Boxes 16-26, 43-45, OV 53; 12.0 linear ft.)
Series 10: Printed Material, circa 1960s-circa 1990s (Boxes 37-39, 45, OVs 48-50, 54, 56, 60; 3.05 linear feet
Series 11: Scrapbooks, 1964-1992 (BVs 61-88; 5.0 linear feet)
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1932-1988, Series 1:; (Boxes 1, 40, OV 58; 1.0 linear ft.)
  This series contains general biographical material on Nesbitt and his family, including records relating to the estates of Nesbitt's parents, Frank and Mildred C. Nesbitt, and Lowell Nesbitt's will. Also found here are records documenting Nesbitt's education, awards that he received, and miscellaneous memorabilia. Temple University records include a yearbook, a photo of Nesbitt, Nesbitt's report card, a certificate of honor, a commencement program, and Nesbitt's Bachelor of Arts and Stained Glass Design certification. The series also includes photographs of a painting and sculpture Nesbitt submitted for his admission to London's Royal College of Art.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by folder title with the exception of records relating to education and awards, which are arranged in rough chronological order.
  - Astrology and Horoscopes, 1969, 1987, undated, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Biographical Information, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Brandeis University Library Learned Research Journal, circa 1970s (Box 1)
  - Car Leasing, circa 1980 (Box 1)
  - Certificate of Occupancy, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Cigar Box, undated, (see Box 40) (Box 1)
  - Driver's License, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Garden Book, undated (Box 1)
  - Interests, undated (Box 1)
  - Lock Information, undated (Box 1)
  - Membership Roster for the Lowell Nesbitt Fan Club (Manhattan Chapter), undated (Box 1)
  - Nesbitt, Frank, Estate, 1932-1982, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Nesbitt, Frank, Memorial, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Nesbitt, Lowell, Will, 1986-1988 (Box 1)
  - Nesbitt, Mildred C., Estate, 1949-1975 (Box 1)
  - Palm Reading of Nesbitt by Jeffrey Norfolk, 1975, (See OV 58) (Box 1)
  - Trip Abroad Book, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Watch and Strap, undated (Box 1)
  - Education and Awards (Box 1)
    - School Papers, circa 1950s (Box 1)
    - Towson High Schook Yearbook, 1948 (Box 1)
    - Towson High School Yearbook, 1951 (Box 1)
    - Towson High School Commencement Program, 1951 (Box 1)
    - High School Diploma, 1951, (see Box 40) (Box 1)
    - Temple University Records, 1955-1957, (6 folders; see also Box 40) (Box 1)
    - Royal College of Art Admission, circa 1955, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Artist Certification, 1985-1988 (Box 1)
    - Dyansen Gallery, Certificate of Honor, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Oversized Cigar Box, undated, (see Box 1) (Box 40 (sol))
  - Oversized Material, Education and Awards, High School Diploma, 1951, (see Box 1) (Box 40 (sol))
  - Oversized Material, Education and Awards, Temple University Tyler Fellow Scroll, 1957, (see Box 1) (Box 40 (sol))
  - Oversized Palm Reading of Nesbitt by Jeffrey Norfolk, 1975, (see Box 1) (Box OV 58)
- Architectural Records for Homes and Studios, 1977-1992, Series 2:; (Boxes 1-2, 40; 1.0 linear ft.)
  This series contains records relating to Nesbitt's homes on West Twelfth Street, New York, New York, and Kent, New York, including documentation of property sales, architectural plans by Preston Phillips, drawings, appraisal photographs and alphabetically arranged correspondence.
  - Architects Drawings, West Twelfth Street, Architecture, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Architectural Plans for Kent Home in New York by Preston Phillips, 1981, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Affidavit and Information on Trash, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Architectural Plans, Pyramid Studio-Garage in Stoneleigh, Kent, New York by Preston Phillips, and Nesbitt's Notes, 1985-1986, (2 folders; see Box 40) (Box 2)
  - Preston Phillips and Kent Home, 1978-1981 (Box 2)
  - List of Paintings for Stoneleigh Pyramid, undated (Box 2)
  - Statement of Closing of Sales of Premises, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Building, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Architectural Records, 1987, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Architectural Plans by Lowell Nesbitt, 1987, (See Box 40) (Box 2)
  - Appraisal Photos, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Kent Studio-A, 1979-1981 (Box 2)
  - Kent Studio-B, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Kent Studio-C, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Kent Studio-EFG, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Kent Studio-H, 1979-1981 (Box 2)
  - Kent Studio-IJ, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Kent Studio-KL, 1979-1981 (Box 2)
  - Kent Studio-MN, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
  - Kent Studio-OP, 1979-1982 (Box 2)
  - Kent Studio-R, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Kent Studio-ST, 1979-1982 (Box 2)
  - Kent Studio-W, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Oversized Architectural Plans, Pyramid Studio-Garage in Stoneleigh, Kent, New York, by Preston Phillips, Nesbitt's Notes, 1985-1986, (2 folders; see Box 2) (Box 40 (sol))
  - Oversized Architectural Plan, Pyramid Studio-Garage in Stoneleigh, Kent, New York, by Preston Phillips, 1985-1986, (see Box 2) (Box 40 (sol))
  - Oversized Architectural Plans by Lowell Nesbitt, 1987, (see Box 2) (Box 40 (sol))
- Notes and Writings, 1981-1990, Series 3:; (Boxes 2-3; 1.0 linear ft.)
  This series contains one folder of writings by Nesbitt in addition to notes on his studios and notebooks and notepads which typically contain "to do" lists, drafts of letters, contact information, and miscellaneous notes. There is also a notebook containing sketches and notes on house planning, and a folder of notes for Pierre Gagne. Studio notebooks contain instructions for Nesbitt's studio assistant, Tim Hoffman.
  - Poem entitled "The Egyptian," Unidentified Author, undated (Box 2)
  - Poem Dedicated to Lowell Nesbitt from Fedil (?), 1983 (Box 2)
  - Writings by Lowell Nesbitt, "Statement of Intuition," undated (Box 2)
  - Notebooks, Notepads and Notes, 1984, undated, (9 folders) (Box 2)
  - Sketches, Notes on House, Planning, Print Material, undated (Box 2)
  - Studio Notes, 1981-1983, (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - Studio Notes, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Notes for Pierre Gagne, 1990 (Box 3)
- Calendars and Addresses, 1973-1993, Series 4:; (Boxes 3-5; 1.25 linear ft.)
  This series contains Nesbitt's notated calendars, such as monthly and yearly planners and "daily reminder" calendars, in addition to address books, telephone numbers and business cards.
  - Address Books, undated, (5 folders) (Box 3)
  - Address Book, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Appointment Books, 1988-1990, (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Business Cards, undated (Box 3)
  - Business Cards and Telephone Numbers, undated, (5 folders) (Box 3)
  - Calendar, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Calendars, 1976-1977, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Calendar, 1978-1984, (7 folders) (Box 4)
  - Calendar, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Calendars, 1991-1992, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Calendar, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Guestbooks and Guest Addresses, circa 1980s, (3 folders) (Box 5)
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1940-circa 1990s, Series 5:; (Boxes 5-12, 40, OV 51; 8.0 linear feet)
  The series is arranged into 6 subseries:
  5.1: Correspondence, 1940-circa 1990s
  5.2: Galleries, 1973-1992
  5.3: Exhibitions, 1981-1992
  5.4: Commissions, 1977-1993
  5.5: Committees, 1980-1992
  5.6: Legal, 1978-1991
  - Correspondence, 1940-circa 1990s, 5.1:
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical, 1940-1992, 5.1.1:
      This subseries contains correspondence with individuals, businesses, organizations and museums arranged alphabetically by folder title. Researchers should also consult 5.1.2: Correspondence: Chronological, for additional correspondence of this type.
      - Albright, Ernest and Madeleine, Chinese Shar-Pei, 1977 (Box 5)
      - Aldrich Museum (1980), Ridgefield, CT, 1979-1981, (2 folders) (Box 5)
      - Anne Letters, circa 1950s, (3 folders) (Box 5)
      - Anti-Defamation League of B-Nai B-Rith, 1991-1992 (Box 5)
      - Arizona Lecture and Tours (1987), 1987-1988, (2 folders) (Box 5)
      - Art Contact, Venezuela-Coconut Grove, Florida, 1978-1980, (2 folders) (Box 5)
      - Arthur Smith Antiques, 1989-1990 (Box 5)
      - Artists for American Indians, American Indian Heritage Foundation, 1991 (Box 5)
      - Atlantic Center for the Arts, New Syrna Beach, FL, 1982-1988 (Box 5)
      - Bace, Bill "Artist Christmas Tree Ornament Benefit and Reception for Friends in Deed," 1992 (Box 5)
      - Baltimore Museum of Art, 1968, 1980-1989, (2 folders) (Box 5)
      - Benetton, John, undated (Box 5)
      - Berger, Larry, 1990 (Box 5)
      - Bianchi, Lynn, undated (Box 5)
      - Brack, Mrs. C. Bernard, undated (Box 5)
      - Bush, Martin H. "ACA Galleries," 1989-1992 (Box 5)
      - Bushnell, George E., Jr., undated (Box 5)
      - Carol and Carol, 1982 (Box 5)
      - Chuzy, Marian, 1992 (Box 5)
      - Clark, Michael and Krausmann, Pamela, 1975 (Box 5)
      - Commonwealth of Virginia, 1991 (Box 5)
      - Contracts and Sales Agreement, 1990 (Box 5)
      - Cook, Edith N., undated (Box 5)
      - Copyrights, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
      - Corporation Art Collections, 1987 (Box 5)
      - Correspondence, Receipts, Address Lists, circa early 1990s (Box 5)
      - Crozier Fine Arts, Inc., 1989 (Box 5)
      - Darling, Reg, 1990 (Box 5)
      - Denver Art Museum, 1992 (Box 5)
      - Edwards, Julie and Blake, 1986 (Box 5)
      - Everson Museum of Art, 1989 (Box 5)
      - Farrell, Kenneth, 1992 (Box 5)
      - Fire Island Pines Arts Project, 1989-1991 (Box 5)
      - Franz Bader, Inc., 1967 (Box 5)
      - Fund for Democracy and Development, 1992 (Box 5)
      - Hightove, John, 1989 (Box 5)
      - Homayoun, Martyn, 1979 (Box 5)
      - House and Garden, Kit Chambers, Nassau, Bahamas, 1980 (Box 5)
      - Huck, Carla, 1993 (Box 5)
      - Images Gallery, 1992 (Box 5)
      - Ivey's Florida, Orlando/Jacksonville, 1980 (Box 5)
      - Jack, "Wells, Rich, Greene Inc," undated (Box 5)
      - Jackson Christmas Card, undated (Box 5)
      - Jackson, Joan, 1989 (Box 5)
      - Jacksonville Arts and Design, 1987 (Box 5)
      - Krausmann, Pamela: see Clark, Michael (Box 5)
      - Leichtung, Jon, 1990 (Box 5)
      - Lejwicks, Grejon, undated (Box 5)
      - Levine and Levine Graphics, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
      - Lilly, David, 1990 (Box 5)
      - Lilly, J. A., Manuscript Satyricon for Roz Avrett, 1991, (4 folders) (Box 5)
      - Lilly, J. A., Satyricon, 1990, (3 folders) (Box 6)
      - Lilly, Jeffrey, Computer Disk, undated (Box 6)
      - Loose Letters Unidentified, circa 1970s-circa 1990s (Box 6)
      - Lowell to Lowell (from), undated (Box 6)
      - Marcus, Roy, undated (Box 6)
      - McLean, Harvey D., undated (Box 6)
      - McNay Art Institute, M. Koogler (1980), San Antonio, TX, 1979-1980, (2 folders) (Box 6)
      - Miami-Dade Public Library, 1987-1991 (Box 6)
      - Miller, Monica, 1991 (Box 6)
      - Morris Museum, Morristown, NJ, 1981-1982 (Box 6)
      - Museum of Art, Fort Lauderdale, FL, 1991 (Box 6)
      - National Arts Club, 1990 (Box 6)
      - Nesbitt, Lenore Carrero, 1987 (Box 6)
      - Nesbitt, Lowell, to his Parents, 1940-1980, (15 folders) (Box 6)
      - Nesbitt, Lowell, from his Parents, 1940-1950 (Box 6)
      - New York Philharmonic, 1987 (Box 6)
      - Pell, Senator Claiborne, 1990 (Box 6)
      - Personal and Professional "Old Correspondence," 1979, (3 folders) (Box 6)
      - Philbrook Museum, Tulsa, OK, 1981-1991 (Box 6)
      - Phillips, Preston, 1992 (Box 6)
      - Pomare, Filipe, 1991 (Box 6)
      - Puchkoff, Carrie, Resume, undated (Box 6)
      - Radford University, 1989 (Box 6)
      - Rich, Matthew, 1989 (Box 6)
      - Terra, undated (Box 6)
      - Towe, Teri Noel, Attorney, 1990-1992 (Box 6)
      - Vanderlip, Dianne Perry, undated (Box 6)
      - Wandel, Peter, 1990 (Box 6)
      - Watson, Sliris (?) and Wid, 1992 (Box 6)
      - Wilson, Bill, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence: Chronological, 1965-1990, 5.1.2:
      This subseries contains corrrespondence with individuals, businesses, organizations and museums arranged in rough chronological order. Researchers should also consult 5.1.1: Correspondence: Alphabetical, for additional correspondence of this type.
      - Correspondence A-Z, 1965-1968, (16 folders) (Box 6)
      - Correspondence A-C, 1971-1973, (2 folders) (Box 6)
      - Correspondence D-Y, 1969-1973, (12 folders) (Box 7)
      - Correspondence A-W, 1973-1975, (12 folders) (Box 7)
      - Correspondence A-Y, 1974-1975, (16 folders) (Box 7)
      - Correspondence A-Y, 1975-1976, (12 folders) (Box 7)
      - Correspondence A-V, 1977-1978, (14 folders) (Box 7)
      - Correspondence W, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
      - Correspondence A-Z, 1979, (14 folders) (Box 8)
      - Correspondence A-W, 1979-1980, (13 folders) (Box 8)
      - Correspondence A-Z, 1981, (15 folders) (Box 8)
      - Correspondence A-W, 1981-1982, (13 folders) (Box 8)
      - Correspondence A-W, 1983, (14 folders) (Box 9)
      - Correspondence A-Z, 1984, (15 folders) (Box 9)
      - Correspondence A-W, 1984-1986, (14 folders) (Box 9)
      - Corresondence A-Z, 1985-1986, (14 folders) (Box 9)
      - Correspondence A-K, 1987, (9 folders) (Box 9)
      - Correspondence L-W, 1987, (7 folders) (Box 10)
      - Correspondence A-Z, 1988, (14 folders) (Box 10)
      - Correspondence A-W, 1989, (15 folders) (Box 10)
      - Correspondence A-W, 1990, (17 folders) (Box 10)
  - Galleries, 1973-1992, 5.2:
    This subseries documents Nesbitt's relationships with a large number of galleries including some that represented him, such as Andrew Crispo Gallery, DiLaurenti Gallery and Fay Gold Gallery, and others throughout the United States and in Germany, who exhibited his work.
    - Andrew Crispo Gallery (New York, NY), 1980-1984, (4 folders) (Box 10)
    - Andrew Crispo Gallery (New York, NY), Consignment Letters, 1978-1979, (3 folders) (Box 10)
    - Andrew Crispo Gallery (New York, NY), Contracts, 1975-1984 (Box 10)
    - Art Collections Gallery (Key West, FL), 1989 (Box 10)
    - Bo Alveryd Gallery (Copenhagen, Denmark), 1974-1981 (Box 10)
    - B. R. Kornblatt Gallery (Baltimore, MD), 1980-1981 (Box 10)
    - DiLaurenti Gallery (New York, NY), 1986, (3 folders) (Box 10)
    - Dyansen Corporation (New York, NY), 1988-1989, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Eleanor Jeck Galleries (Tucson, AZ), 1987 (Box 10)
    - El Prado Gallery, Don Pierson (Sedona, AZ),1987 (Box 10)
    - Fay Gold Gallery, 1987 (Box 10)
    - Foster Harmon Gallery (Sarasota, FL), 1985-1986 (Box 10)
    - Galerie Vorburg-Herman (Wunsche, Germany), 1984 (Box 10)
    - Gallery Henoch, 1991 (Box 10)
    - Gallery of 24 (Bay Harbor, FL), 1984-1985 (Box 10)
    - Gimpel, Weitzenhofer and Cravan, 1973-1974 (Box 10)
    - H. R. Love Gallery (Chicago, IL), 1987 (Box 10)
    - Images Gallery, (Toledo, OH), 1982-1990 (Box 10)
    - Joy Tash Gallery (Scottsdale, AZ), 1987-1991 (Box 10)
    - Kaffie Gallery (Corpus Christie, TX), 1981-1982 (Box 10)
    - Larsen-Dulman Gallery (New Hope, PA), 1988 (Box 10)
    - Louis Newman Galleries (Beverly Hills, CA), 1987-1988, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Martin Lawrence Gallery, M. Binder (Van Nuys, CA), 1983-1986 (Box 10)
    - Metropolitan Art Associates Graphics and Contracts, circa 1980 (Box 10)
    - Perri-Reneth Gallery (Southamption, NY), 1985-1989 (Box 11)
    - Post Oak Fine Art Co. (Houston, TX), 1981-1982 (Box 11)
    - Reinhard Onnasch-Bjorn Herder, Berlin, Germany, 1983 (Box 11)
    - Robert F. Kidd Gallery (Birmingham, MI), 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    - Robert Samuel Gallery, 1979 (Box 11)
    - Sander Fine Art, G. Beker (Daytona Beach, FL), 1984-1987 (Box 11)
    - Sarasota Design Gallery, 1992 (Box 11)
    - Southwest Gallery (Dallas, TX), 1981-1983 (Box 11)
    - Stadt Aachen Neue Galerie IM Alten Kurhausm Klischee and Antiklischee (New Gallery in the Cure House, Aachen), undated (Box 11)
    - Steiner Galleries (Miami, FL), 1987-1989 (Box 11)
    - Steven Scott Gallery (Baltimore, MD), 1988-1989 (Box 11)
    - Ted Gallery, 1989 (Box 11)
    - Texann Ivy Fine Arts (1983) (Orlando, FL), 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    - Uddoh Gallery, 1989 (Box 11)
    - Wally Findlay Gallery (Palm Beach, FL), 1986-1988 (Box 11)
  - Exhibitions, 1981-1992, 5.3:
    This subseries documents a variety of exhibitions in which Nesbitt took part or which he curated such as the 1990 Humanist Icon exhibition at Bayly Art Museum in Charlottesville, Virginia that traveled to the New York Academy of Art and the Edwin A. Ulrich Museum of Art at Wichita State University, Wichita, Kansas.
    - Animal Garden Exhibition, Andrew Crispo Gallery, 1981 (Box 11)
    - Art in the Embassies, Truman Hall, 1985 (Box 11)
    - Baltimore Itinerary for Exhibition Receptions, undated (Box 11)
    - Gadsen Alabama Exhibition, undated, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Gadsen Center for Cultural Arts, Gadsen, AL, 1989-1990 (Box 11)
    - General Electric Show (1981), Fairfield, CT, 1981 (Box 11)
    - Greenwich Garden Center (1983), Cos Cob, CT, 1983 (Box 11)
    - Humanist Icon (Box 11)
      - Bayly Museum, University of Virginia, circa 1990, (2 folders) (Box 11)
      - Collage of Works, 1990, (see OV 51) (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, John Chamberlain, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, Ivan Chermayeff, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, Lewis Davis, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, Michelle Oka Doner, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, Helen Drellich, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, Molissa Fenley, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, Katherine Goldsmith, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, Geoffrey Holder, 1990 (Box 11)